<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator>
  
  
  <link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2019-10-31T22:57:34+00:00</updated>
  <id>//</id>

  
    <title type="html">palus weſtmonasterienſis</title>
  

  

  
    <author>
        <name>Joshua Loo</name>
      
      
    </author>
  

  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Tomorrow, in Abbey</title>
      
      
      <link href="/2019/10/31/abbey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tomorrow, in Abbey" />
      
      <published>2019-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/2019/10/31/abbey</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/2019/10/31/abbey/">&lt;p&gt;There is much else I should like to say, especially about treatment of Mainland people. The Chaplain has been very helpful. I have had to cut some things, and what I am left with is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first line of “March of the Volunteers”, the Chinese national anthem, reads&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Arise, ye who refuse to be slaves!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in recent years at Westminster, democratic political views and values have come to be perceived as somehow opposed to Chinese ethnic identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How has this happened?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By one side, China is seen as a despotic régime, descended from that of Chairman Mao. It sees tens of millions of deaths and the myriad of atrocities that collectively overwhelm the human imagination: being forced to kill one’s parents, starvation, and the many tortures invented by millions of human minds bent to the most inhuman of purposes. Today it sees a fundamental unfairness, from concentration camps for Muslims to a lack of recourse when homes are demolished and lungs are poisoned by thoughtless development. Closer to home there are worries that opening a school in China could open us to pressure to curtail the freedom of expression we hold so dear at Westminster. Recent news from Blizzard, the National Basketball Association, and Apple is not encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other side? Here is a thought experiment. Suppose that a hundred of us were sent to a school in India. How would we feel if out of the blue we were asked: “Were your grandparents there at the Amritsar massacre?” “Why do you support the British government when it sells bombs to Saudi Arabia for killing families in Yemen?” “Did you support torture in Britain’s colonial war on the Mau Mau in Kenya?” “Look at the treatment of the Windrush generation. Are all Brits racist?” “What about your betrayal of the people of Diego Garcia?” “Why don’t you realise you are indoctrinated?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In sum, this sort of discourse reduces people to nations, and nations to the worst aspects of their governments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would make two observations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, there is a clear distinction between sensible political discussion about China and Sinophobia. Often, to replace “Chinese government” with “the Chinese” is enough to go from something that could be said in a calm conversation to nonsense about ‘a clash of civilisations’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can all try to find common premises. In moral questions, we can perhaps all agree that ultimately we should strive for fairness, freedom from want, and even human rights. And when discussing how to achieve these aims, we can all recognise the human frailty and selfishness of ruling classes, whether politicians or businessmen, and everyone’s fallibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genuine political discussion isn’t a game, your interlocutor is not the Chinese government, and a cheap rhetorical victory doesn’t free Tibet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, to simply avoid difficult issues is a false economy. A common narrative assigns deference and discipline to China, and open debate to the West. But the history of China is one of peasant revolts just as indicative of a desire for freedom as anything in the history of the West. And it was because of patriotism and the desire for freedom that we resisted the forces of Imperial Japan in 1937. Were we wrong to refuse to bow down?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we should discuss the many difficulties of modern China. To do so without acrimony is entirely possible. It is a very Chinese tradition. And it clearly does not need to involve Sinophobia. We must not make excuses for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Westminster is a bubble. Regrettably, most are shut out. But in its protective embrace, let us try to have some of the discussions that the world needs but too often doesn’t want to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Joshua Loo</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="speeches etc" />
      

      
        <category term="westminster" />
      
        <category term="sinophobia" />
      
        <category term="china" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">There is much else I should like to say, especially about treatment of Mainland people. The Chaplain has been very helpful. I have had to cut some things, and what I am left with is as follows: The first line of “March of the Volunteers”, the Chinese national anthem, reads “Arise, ye who refuse to be slaves!” But in recent years at Westminster, democratic political views and values have come to be perceived as somehow opposed to Chinese ethnic identity. How has this happened? By one side, China is seen as a despotic régime, descended from that of Chairman Mao. It sees tens of millions of deaths and the myriad of atrocities that collectively overwhelm the human imagination: being forced to kill one’s parents, starvation, and the many tortures invented by millions of human minds bent to the most inhuman of purposes. Today it sees a fundamental unfairness, from concentration camps for Muslims to a lack of recourse when homes are demolished and lungs are poisoned by thoughtless development. Closer to home there are worries that opening a school in China could open us to pressure to curtail the freedom of expression we hold so dear at Westminster. Recent news from Blizzard, the National Basketball Association, and Apple is not encouraging. The other side? Here is a thought experiment. Suppose that a hundred of us were sent to a school in India. How would we feel if out of the blue we were asked: “Were your grandparents there at the Amritsar massacre?” “Why do you support the British government when it sells bombs to Saudi Arabia for killing families in Yemen?” “Did you support torture in Britain’s colonial war on the Mau Mau in Kenya?” “Look at the treatment of the Windrush generation. Are all Brits racist?” “What about your betrayal of the people of Diego Garcia?” “Why don’t you realise you are indoctrinated?” In sum, this sort of discourse reduces people to nations, and nations to the worst aspects of their governments. I would make two observations. First, there is a clear distinction between sensible political discussion about China and Sinophobia. Often, to replace “Chinese government” with “the Chinese” is enough to go from something that could be said in a calm conversation to nonsense about ‘a clash of civilisations’. We can all try to find common premises. In moral questions, we can perhaps all agree that ultimately we should strive for fairness, freedom from want, and even human rights. And when discussing how to achieve these aims, we can all recognise the human frailty and selfishness of ruling classes, whether politicians or businessmen, and everyone’s fallibility. Genuine political discussion isn’t a game, your interlocutor is not the Chinese government, and a cheap rhetorical victory doesn’t free Tibet. Second, to simply avoid difficult issues is a false economy. A common narrative assigns deference and discipline to China, and open debate to the West. But the history of China is one of peasant revolts just as indicative of a desire for freedom as anything in the history of the West. And it was because of patriotism and the desire for freedom that we resisted the forces of Imperial Japan in 1937. Were we wrong to refuse to bow down? So we should discuss the many difficulties of modern China. To do so without acrimony is entirely possible. It is a very Chinese tradition. And it clearly does not need to involve Sinophobia. We must not make excuses for ourselves. Westminster is a bubble. Regrettably, most are shut out. But in its protective embrace, let us try to have some of the discussions that the world needs but too often doesn’t want to have.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Diary: some old entries on Hong Kong</title>
      
      
      <link href="/2019/10/23/hong-kong-diary/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Diary: some old entries on Hong Kong" />
      
      <published>2019-10-23T00:00:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2019-10-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>/2019/10/23/hong-kong-diary</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/2019/10/23/hong-kong-diary/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;june&quot;&gt;13 June&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, a million marched in Hong Kong against a bill that would permit extradition, to, inter alia, mainland China. The usual suspects of course appeared: pan-Democratic veterans, independence supporters, and students; but as the international press do not tire of noting, businesses, former officials, and even religious groups find themselves concerned by the bill. The risk is to Hong Kong qua Hong Kong, i.e., the only free Chinese city outside Taiwan on earth, and the legal innovation that Hong Kong’s common law represents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday also saw perhaps thousands marching in overseas; in London, about 4,000 appeared at a protest organised by a group called “Democracy for Hong Kong” (D4HK). On Thursday, it delivered a letter to the Foreign and Commonwealth Office, urging the British government to discharge its moral and legal duties to the people of Hong Kong. The principal demands made were further statements against the bill, a clear condemnation of police violence in the week after Sunday, a coalition with other governments to oppose the bill, a declaration of a breach of the Sino-British Joint Declaration in the event that the bill is passed, the inclusion of civil liberties in any trade deal with China, and action to protect the rights of holders of British National (Overseas) passports in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those attending the protest were largely Cantonese-speaking Hong Kong people; some appeared to be tourists, carrying suitcases, whilst others were students or seemed to live here. Many of the protesters were carrying images of injuries from rubber bullets and beatings by the police. The Hong Kong police, once called “Asia’s finest”, can still justifiably be called some of the most restrained in East Asia: no live bullets have been used yet, for example, and a million marched with about ten arrests on Sunday. But even the staunchest pacifist must have some sympathy with the rage that some felt on seeing footage of the police beating those who had already been subdued, firing tear gas cannisters and rubber bullets but metres away from others without aiming upwards, and corralling journalists. As one French photojournalist remarked, he thought that he was in Hong Kong—the police weren’t supposed to shoot at them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not entirely sure whether I should attend in the first place; I am not from Hong Kong, after all—I do not even speak Cantonese, as I was reminded on arrival. This was, however, somewhat fortuitous, as it meant that when an organiser told those attending of a plan, I ended up in conversation with him after asking for an English translation. I suppose in the end I decided to go not because I was opposed to some internal domestic affair in Hong Kong that isn’t going the way I want, but rather because lawn bowls was cancelled, I had a rather uncomfortable feeling on seeing images of police violence in Central, a friend from Hong Kong didn’t want to go for fear of being photographed, and I very much feel that Chinese everywhere—even those who can be called “ang moh” by their Singaporean relatives with some justification—sink or swim together—if autonomous communities do not show strength towards the CCP they will simply be absorbed, and what hope there is of a better China dissolved in that process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the reaction of my friend shows a somewhat disturbing trend from 2014. In 2014 the police did not move as rapidly; one analyst thinks that relatively sympathetic types were retired quickly, though I have not had time to look at the situation—but this is not the same police force that operated under a Secretary whose retirement in 1998 was allegedly due to his refusal to coöperate with Mainland officials. As The Guardian notes, protesters are increasingly wary of cameras, less idealistic, and more likely to resort to violence. Now Hong Kong has lost the carefree attitude of 1989, when 1.5 million protesters crowded the streets and businessmen and bankers could wear black without feeling that their jobs were under threat—when journalists at a pro-Beijing newspaper elicited cheers on waving to the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scenes of this sort are reminiscent of disturbances when blacks are shot in the United States: the police thrash, fire tear gas, and generally behave in a terribly uncivilised manner. Some might suggest that there is therefore nothing wrong with what is happening in Hong Kong. This is nonsense, because Hong Kong is a perfectly civilised place and should not therefore hold itself to the barbarian standards of a declining empire. But I am also not entirely sure that even American police officers would fire rubber bullets at people several metres away; and certainly in the United Kingdom the police normally only have batons. I remember watching a solitary police officer with a single cone preventing some protesters in drivers from reaching Parliament Square; Britain and Hong Kong share a capacity to behave in this civilised fashion, where protests take place without excessive violence from either side—and that the protest on Sunday passed without violence suggests that the police are to blame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the other trend is a growing diversity. It used to be that the Civil Human Rights Front and the orthodox democrats operated within the legal framework in a very strict sense. They still do, but they are quite happy to rub shoulders with their more violent counterparts. The march on Sunday could not have reached a turnout of a million without substantial unity between independence supporters, orthodox pan-Democrats, and relatively apolitical people who still in some sense value Hong Kong qua Hong Kong. I cannot pretend to be entirely comfortable with all the sentiment expressed. “Hong Kong is not China!” ran one declaration—at its worst, an expression of a xenophobic and irrational sentiment towards entirely economically necessary migration and those seeking a better life, and an escape from the unfortunate truth that Hong Kong independence makes democracy less likely, in that to achieve mere democracy would require the establishment of a political climate that would still not be sufficient to manage the breakup of the motherland. And on that banner there was a British colonial flag; clearly, those holding it do not remember that the charges under which many have been charged in recent days were created by the British (as Hong Kong Watch’s report on the amusingly named Public Order Ordinance makes clear), or for that matter how the 1967 riots were dealt with. British rule certainly improved near the end—the 1995 elections were the only point at which the pan-Democrats had a legislative majority reflective of the level of public support for them, but colonial nostalgia does not really seem to be an appropriate response to neocolonialism..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, one could demand further elucidation as to why I should feel entitled to comment on the views of Hong Kong people—and to that, I do not really have an answer. As Amia Srinivasan quite clearly elucidates in a paper titled “The Aptness of Anger”, we do not measure anger by its efficacy—it is often simply apt as a reaction. And if some from Hong Kong in their anger accidentally endorse a symbol of a harmful past that has little further power, it is perhaps almost counterproductive to argue. Those who are about to be crushed can hardly be begrudged a little xenophobia. My discomfort is compounded by a likely uncharitable interpretation of one person’s eagerness to hold Benedict Rogers’ bag; in the mode of analysis of the anti-colonial left that is all too often the luxury of those who frankly did quite well out of the whole business of empire, the sight of a Chinese woman eagerly seeking to serve a white Briton was discomforting. Another complained to me of what might best be described as her excessive enthusiasm, which I shall not describe further to avoid identification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We fairly awkwardly assembled outside 7 Charles Street. Once Benedict Rogers arrived, a D4HK spokesman and he delivered statements. Nobody from the press was there, but that is unsurprising given that turnout was almost certainly under 100, and probably not much more than 40—at least in my likely inaccurate estimation. Once the speeches concluded, we chanted “No extradition to China” and various other slogans—though it is notable that everyone chanted “Hong Kong is not China” with equal vigour, with the exception of me, because I am not even sure that Hong Kong society has come to a definitive conclusion on that matter, and proper operation of One Country Two Systems would hardly be undemocratic. Benedict Rogers and the D4HK people then walked into the FCO and spent a seemingly inordinate length of the therein—quite why, I am not entirely sure—before emerging; we then walked to Downing Street to shout slogans some more. Some photos are taken, but many were reluctant to be photographed; material on the Facebook page of D4HK shows many holding up photos to obscure their faces. They are the more courageous ones. At Downing Street a fairly jovial fellow from the Metropolitan Police asks whether he can do anything and when we intend to disperse. I am not particularly kindly inclined to police officers in general, who seem to spend an awful lot of time doing various silly or morally indefensible things like disturbing black people and demanding bribes, instead of investigating burglaries, but this one seemed relatively peaceable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outcome of the struggle is not yet clear. The President of the Legislative Council has postponed debate for two days in a row; indications in the South China Morning Post, a paper with impeccable establishment credentials as well as a still credible news-reporting operation, are that the second reading is for now not an immediate priority for the pro-Beijing camp, though the government shows no signs of definitively retracting the bill. But the sad outcome of these events is that Hong Kong has become a nastier, more violent, and more disunited society over the past few days. I doubt that the police will ever regain the trust that they lost when they threatened to fire on a mother asking them to act in a peaceful fashion, when they arrested protesters in hospital on suspicion of rioting despite their still being injured, and when they started firing even without the normal sign demanding that the crowd should disperse. Will a peaceful march of the sort that occurred on Sunday ever happen again? Fortunately, the legislative framework does not have a particularly effective ouster clause preventing judicial oversight of the decisions of the Commissioner concerning popular assembly. Yet we see also here the virtues of Hong Kong: tenacity and defiance in the face of a hopeless situation seems to have stopped the bill at least for a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong has never been master of its own destiny, and nothing has changed that fundamental fact in the past few days. A long-term prognosis would not be particularly optimistic. But even in the face of such poor prospects, Hong Kong still refuses to fall silent—perhaps in the hope that they will be remembered by history; in the new China, that is an utterly forlorn hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the protest I place a poster reading “No China Extradition” on the door of a friend’s dormitory—we are both fairly sceptical of the CCP. One scholar complained: I was initially worried that I had accidentally stuck up a poster endorsing some of the more reactionary views held in Hong Kong at present, because I had neglected to scan the QR code—but that turned out to link to a reasonably accurate BBC article that repeated what different sides had said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The argument for the extradition bill goes something like this: bad people in China often flee to Hong Kong, and can get off scot free due to the lack of an extradition agreement. The bill would solve this gap, and so help to stop corruption on the Mainland. This is superficially plausible. However, the extradition bill would be highly unlikely to achieve the goal of reducing corruption for at least three reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the behaviour that the bill would deter is not corruption. It rather discourages behaviour that would result in being charged for corruption or murder or something else. There is ample evidence to suggest that the anti-corruption effort is principally being used for political ends—Xi’s family is suspiciously rich, after all. The extradition bill would therefore simply encourage loyalty. If anything, mudslinging between party factions is very good, because it ensures that each side has an incentive to appeal to external actors (business, intellectuals, and so on) by being less corrupt. All that is reduced when Hong Kong is no longer safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, the most corrupt would not flee to Hong Kong—they can flee to the West. Most corruption is presumably due to the actions of a very small élite; Hong Kong would see prosecuted some small fish, but few big fish. Moreover Mainland authorities have effective control of all emigration, so the only people affected would have managed to escape the authorities’ notice until they had left the country. And finally, Hong Kong visas are no easier to obtain than those to other foreign countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, the effective operation of the much-vaunted safeguards that would remain in s. 5 of the Fugitive Offenders Ordinance would preclude most extradition. If the courts take a reasonable view of what “political” cases are, they will rule out most extraditions of corrupt officials, since most of them will be brought to court as a result of infighting. The only situation in which the benefit from extradition would outweigh the inevitable unrest concomitant on the failure of such safeguards to operate would be in attempts to silence particularly effective dissidents or the highest-ranking officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But our anonymous friends also wonder what the risk to Hong Kong is. At the moment Hong Kong has the most powerful opposition movement in all of China. This is not a situation with which the CCP is happy: that is why pan-democrats are often denied entry to China and attacked in state media, and why the state continues to pay the political price of avoiding democracy. An extradition bill would simply require a prima facie case for what would effectively amount to a kidnapping: all sorts of cases can be concocted, and judges convinced. A few exemplary cases against Martin Lee, Tanya Chan, and Joshua Wong would be enough to cow Hong Kong—and deprive it of some of its more effective leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong is, however, supposed to be part of China—shouldn’t it therefore serve it? The process of the formation of identity is almost universally traumatic—it is undeniable that Hong Kong’s divergence from the Mainland was precipitated by the British. But we should take identities as we find them to a very great extent; we do not question the English identity because of the harrying of the north or the German identity when it was secured by blood. Identities should be judged by their present effect; the present effect of the Hong Kong identity is to demand freedom. And it is unclear why the central government is the legitimate representative of the Chinese people in the first place; it is not meaningfully elected and goes to great lengths to conceal what can be revealed about the true extent of support for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is another consideration. Even if the bill has a minimal effect, it is still one more step in the salami-slicing strategy of the central government—and the only way to stop such slicing is to resist very firmly every single attempt, even if it seems disproportionate to do so. There will never be tanks or live ammunition in Hong Kong, so to simply wait till there are and then resist would be a thoroughly misguided strategy: one would simply have waited until an arrest on a charge probably concocted in the common law somewhere before being jailed in a still relatively humane jail—but with the consequence that one’s ability to dissent has been curtailed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;further-reflexions&quot;&gt;Further reflexions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tension, and violence, escalated substantially in the aftermath of the visit to the Foreign Office. On 9 June, an estimated million marched, in a city of seven million. If there were ten million on the streets of the United Kingdom no government would last; but the government did not respond. The Wednesday thereafter the second reading of the bill was indefinitely suspended, after violent clashes at the Legislative Council. The police have, in my view rightly, been blamed for escalation then. That same day, it was announced that the second reading of the bill had been indefinitely suspended. On Sunday, two million marched, and an apology was issued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been a series of further clashes. Both protesters and police have been inordinately violent to each other, though in many cases it seems that the police created a wide environment of desensitisation to violence. This is true of the environment as a whole: substantial violence first occurred when the police attacked protesters outside the Legislative Council on 12 June. But it is also broadly true of individual incidents; the police did not need to enter New Town Plaza, whence the most galling and distressing footage has emerged. This is not to excuse the behaviour of individual protesters, who in one case seem to have very badly thrashed one policeman. Perhaps appropriate, it was a journalist who protected him, shouting that he was from Hong Kong too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commentators have become increasingly distressed by this pattern of violence. It is tempting to blame protesters or police, and in individual cases this diagnosis is correct. That, however, would be to ignore the rôle of the Chief Executive in encouraging it. A leadership who truly support Hong Kong’s proud and still extant tradition of peaceful protest would not have withdrawn the bill only after violent clashes, having ignored the voice of a million people, nor would it have required the police to withdraw from a relatively defensible position in the Legislative Council, thus allowing protesters to damage the building. The message of a Chief Executive who relents only when the Legislative Council is besieged is that peaceful marches will be ignored; only violence will attract the attention of the authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, there is good reason to suspect that this is deliberate. First of all, Beijing are paying attention; the South China Morning Post has regularly reported on the despatch of special working groups from Beijing, and pro-Beijing newspapers have reported on the holding of meetings in Shenzhen, with one even including the Chief Executive herself. Second, it is relatively clear what the principal elements of such a plan would be. In allowing and encouraging protesters, Carrie Lam hopes to reduce overall public support for dissidents, with the end of rendering them a small minority who can easily be suppressed when the time is ripe. Violent clashes serve no purpose other than that of the establishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reflects an utterly contemptible attitude on the part of the Executive Council to Hong Kong. It is the height of irresponsibility to encourage the destruction of one of the most civilised political cultures in the world for short-term political gain. Pro-establishment types should think very carefully about continued support for this strategy: very few of them genuinely believe that Hong Kong is not ready for universal suffrage or a little redistribution—they support Beijing because they believe in a strategy of limited appeasement to maintain what freedoms they have. If the pan-democrats are successfully sidelined, there will be nobody left to stand up to Beijing other than them; they will no longer receive the patronage of the United Front and the Liaison Office, and will have to face Beijing’s anger—from a position of considerably greater inexperience than that of the pan-democrats. The Chief Executive risks the destruction of Hong Kong qua Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are these people really protesters? Martin Lee suggested not on Radio 4’s Today programme. He may well be right; there is nothing to stop the United Front or HKSAR government from sending provocateurs to implement the strategy outlined above. But there is also nothing to rule out that there are very many genuine protesters amongst the violent. The anger that seethed through students at a recent meeting in Hong Kong University when Mainland students spoke was not the ephemeral product of internal university complaints. A large part of Hong Kong is unspeakably angered by the police, government, and Beijing. Some of them have lost hope due to economic conditions. It is all too plausible that some have been driven to the point of thrashing the police, and that they are not in fact principally provocateurs.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Joshua Loo</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="diary" />
      

      
        <category term="hong kong" />
      
        <category term="extradition law" />
      
        <category term="police" />
      
        <category term="law" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">13 June On Sunday, a million marched in Hong Kong against a bill that would permit extradition, to, inter alia, mainland China. The usual suspects of course appeared: pan-Democratic veterans, independence supporters, and students; but as the international press do not tire of noting, businesses, former officials, and even religious groups find themselves concerned by the bill. The risk is to Hong Kong qua Hong Kong, i.e., the only free Chinese city outside Taiwan on earth, and the legal innovation that Hong Kong’s common law represents. Sunday also saw perhaps thousands marching in overseas; in London, about 4,000 appeared at a protest organised by a group called “Democracy for Hong Kong” (D4HK). On Thursday, it delivered a letter to the Foreign and Commonwealth Office, urging the British government to discharge its moral and legal duties to the people of Hong Kong. The principal demands made were further statements against the bill, a clear condemnation of police violence in the week after Sunday, a coalition with other governments to oppose the bill, a declaration of a breach of the Sino-British Joint Declaration in the event that the bill is passed, the inclusion of civil liberties in any trade deal with China, and action to protect the rights of holders of British National (Overseas) passports in Hong Kong. Those attending the protest were largely Cantonese-speaking Hong Kong people; some appeared to be tourists, carrying suitcases, whilst others were students or seemed to live here. Many of the protesters were carrying images of injuries from rubber bullets and beatings by the police. The Hong Kong police, once called “Asia’s finest”, can still justifiably be called some of the most restrained in East Asia: no live bullets have been used yet, for example, and a million marched with about ten arrests on Sunday. But even the staunchest pacifist must have some sympathy with the rage that some felt on seeing footage of the police beating those who had already been subdued, firing tear gas cannisters and rubber bullets but metres away from others without aiming upwards, and corralling journalists. As one French photojournalist remarked, he thought that he was in Hong Kong—the police weren’t supposed to shoot at them. I was not entirely sure whether I should attend in the first place; I am not from Hong Kong, after all—I do not even speak Cantonese, as I was reminded on arrival. This was, however, somewhat fortuitous, as it meant that when an organiser told those attending of a plan, I ended up in conversation with him after asking for an English translation. I suppose in the end I decided to go not because I was opposed to some internal domestic affair in Hong Kong that isn’t going the way I want, but rather because lawn bowls was cancelled, I had a rather uncomfortable feeling on seeing images of police violence in Central, a friend from Hong Kong didn’t want to go for fear of being photographed, and I very much feel that Chinese everywhere—even those who can be called “ang moh” by their Singaporean relatives with some justification—sink or swim together—if autonomous communities do not show strength towards the CCP they will simply be absorbed, and what hope there is of a better China dissolved in that process. And the reaction of my friend shows a somewhat disturbing trend from 2014. In 2014 the police did not move as rapidly; one analyst thinks that relatively sympathetic types were retired quickly, though I have not had time to look at the situation—but this is not the same police force that operated under a Secretary whose retirement in 1998 was allegedly due to his refusal to coöperate with Mainland officials. As The Guardian notes, protesters are increasingly wary of cameras, less idealistic, and more likely to resort to violence. Now Hong Kong has lost the carefree attitude of 1989, when 1.5 million protesters crowded the streets and businessmen and bankers could wear black without feeling that their jobs were under threat—when journalists at a pro-Beijing newspaper elicited cheers on waving to the crowd. Scenes of this sort are reminiscent of disturbances when blacks are shot in the United States: the police thrash, fire tear gas, and generally behave in a terribly uncivilised manner. Some might suggest that there is therefore nothing wrong with what is happening in Hong Kong. This is nonsense, because Hong Kong is a perfectly civilised place and should not therefore hold itself to the barbarian standards of a declining empire. But I am also not entirely sure that even American police officers would fire rubber bullets at people several metres away; and certainly in the United Kingdom the police normally only have batons. I remember watching a solitary police officer with a single cone preventing some protesters in drivers from reaching Parliament Square; Britain and Hong Kong share a capacity to behave in this civilised fashion, where protests take place without excessive violence from either side—and that the protest on Sunday passed without violence suggests that the police are to blame. But the other trend is a growing diversity. It used to be that the Civil Human Rights Front and the orthodox democrats operated within the legal framework in a very strict sense. They still do, but they are quite happy to rub shoulders with their more violent counterparts. The march on Sunday could not have reached a turnout of a million without substantial unity between independence supporters, orthodox pan-Democrats, and relatively apolitical people who still in some sense value Hong Kong qua Hong Kong. I cannot pretend to be entirely comfortable with all the sentiment expressed. “Hong Kong is not China!” ran one declaration—at its worst, an expression of a xenophobic and irrational sentiment towards entirely economically necessary migration and those seeking a better life, and an escape from the unfortunate truth that Hong Kong independence makes democracy less likely, in that to achieve mere democracy would require the establishment of a political climate that would still not be sufficient to manage the breakup of the motherland. And on that banner there was a British colonial flag; clearly, those holding it do not remember that the charges under which many have been charged in recent days were created by the British (as Hong Kong Watch’s report on the amusingly named Public Order Ordinance makes clear), or for that matter how the 1967 riots were dealt with. British rule certainly improved near the end—the 1995 elections were the only point at which the pan-Democrats had a legislative majority reflective of the level of public support for them, but colonial nostalgia does not really seem to be an appropriate response to neocolonialism.. At the same time, one could demand further elucidation as to why I should feel entitled to comment on the views of Hong Kong people—and to that, I do not really have an answer. As Amia Srinivasan quite clearly elucidates in a paper titled “The Aptness of Anger”, we do not measure anger by its efficacy—it is often simply apt as a reaction. And if some from Hong Kong in their anger accidentally endorse a symbol of a harmful past that has little further power, it is perhaps almost counterproductive to argue. Those who are about to be crushed can hardly be begrudged a little xenophobia. My discomfort is compounded by a likely uncharitable interpretation of one person’s eagerness to hold Benedict Rogers’ bag; in the mode of analysis of the anti-colonial left that is all too often the luxury of those who frankly did quite well out of the whole business of empire, the sight of a Chinese woman eagerly seeking to serve a white Briton was discomforting. Another complained to me of what might best be described as her excessive enthusiasm, which I shall not describe further to avoid identification. We fairly awkwardly assembled outside 7 Charles Street. Once Benedict Rogers arrived, a D4HK spokesman and he delivered statements. Nobody from the press was there, but that is unsurprising given that turnout was almost certainly under 100, and probably not much more than 40—at least in my likely inaccurate estimation. Once the speeches concluded, we chanted “No extradition to China” and various other slogans—though it is notable that everyone chanted “Hong Kong is not China” with equal vigour, with the exception of me, because I am not even sure that Hong Kong society has come to a definitive conclusion on that matter, and proper operation of One Country Two Systems would hardly be undemocratic. Benedict Rogers and the D4HK people then walked into the FCO and spent a seemingly inordinate length of the therein—quite why, I am not entirely sure—before emerging; we then walked to Downing Street to shout slogans some more. Some photos are taken, but many were reluctant to be photographed; material on the Facebook page of D4HK shows many holding up photos to obscure their faces. They are the more courageous ones. At Downing Street a fairly jovial fellow from the Metropolitan Police asks whether he can do anything and when we intend to disperse. I am not particularly kindly inclined to police officers in general, who seem to spend an awful lot of time doing various silly or morally indefensible things like disturbing black people and demanding bribes, instead of investigating burglaries, but this one seemed relatively peaceable. The outcome of the struggle is not yet clear. The President of the Legislative Council has postponed debate for two days in a row; indications in the South China Morning Post, a paper with impeccable establishment credentials as well as a still credible news-reporting operation, are that the second reading is for now not an immediate priority for the pro-Beijing camp, though the government shows no signs of definitively retracting the bill. But the sad outcome of these events is that Hong Kong has become a nastier, more violent, and more disunited society over the past few days. I doubt that the police will ever regain the trust that they lost when they threatened to fire on a mother asking them to act in a peaceful fashion, when they arrested protesters in hospital on suspicion of rioting despite their still being injured, and when they started firing even without the normal sign demanding that the crowd should disperse. Will a peaceful march of the sort that occurred on Sunday ever happen again? Fortunately, the legislative framework does not have a particularly effective ouster clause preventing judicial oversight of the decisions of the Commissioner concerning popular assembly. Yet we see also here the virtues of Hong Kong: tenacity and defiance in the face of a hopeless situation seems to have stopped the bill at least for a few days. Hong Kong has never been master of its own destiny, and nothing has changed that fundamental fact in the past few days. A long-term prognosis would not be particularly optimistic. But even in the face of such poor prospects, Hong Kong still refuses to fall silent—perhaps in the hope that they will be remembered by history; in the new China, that is an utterly forlorn hope. After the protest I place a poster reading “No China Extradition” on the door of a friend’s dormitory—we are both fairly sceptical of the CCP. One scholar complained: I was initially worried that I had accidentally stuck up a poster endorsing some of the more reactionary views held in Hong Kong at present, because I had neglected to scan the QR code—but that turned out to link to a reasonably accurate BBC article that repeated what different sides had said. The argument for the extradition bill goes something like this: bad people in China often flee to Hong Kong, and can get off scot free due to the lack of an extradition agreement. The bill would solve this gap, and so help to stop corruption on the Mainland. This is superficially plausible. However, the extradition bill would be highly unlikely to achieve the goal of reducing corruption for at least three reasons. First, the behaviour that the bill would deter is not corruption. It rather discourages behaviour that would result in being charged for corruption or murder or something else. There is ample evidence to suggest that the anti-corruption effort is principally being used for political ends—Xi’s family is suspiciously rich, after all. The extradition bill would therefore simply encourage loyalty. If anything, mudslinging between party factions is very good, because it ensures that each side has an incentive to appeal to external actors (business, intellectuals, and so on) by being less corrupt. All that is reduced when Hong Kong is no longer safe. Second, the most corrupt would not flee to Hong Kong—they can flee to the West. Most corruption is presumably due to the actions of a very small élite; Hong Kong would see prosecuted some small fish, but few big fish. Moreover Mainland authorities have effective control of all emigration, so the only people affected would have managed to escape the authorities’ notice until they had left the country. And finally, Hong Kong visas are no easier to obtain than those to other foreign countries. Third, the effective operation of the much-vaunted safeguards that would remain in s. 5 of the Fugitive Offenders Ordinance would preclude most extradition. If the courts take a reasonable view of what “political” cases are, they will rule out most extraditions of corrupt officials, since most of them will be brought to court as a result of infighting. The only situation in which the benefit from extradition would outweigh the inevitable unrest concomitant on the failure of such safeguards to operate would be in attempts to silence particularly effective dissidents or the highest-ranking officials. But our anonymous friends also wonder what the risk to Hong Kong is. At the moment Hong Kong has the most powerful opposition movement in all of China. This is not a situation with which the CCP is happy: that is why pan-democrats are often denied entry to China and attacked in state media, and why the state continues to pay the political price of avoiding democracy. An extradition bill would simply require a prima facie case for what would effectively amount to a kidnapping: all sorts of cases can be concocted, and judges convinced. A few exemplary cases against Martin Lee, Tanya Chan, and Joshua Wong would be enough to cow Hong Kong—and deprive it of some of its more effective leaders. Hong Kong is, however, supposed to be part of China—shouldn’t it therefore serve it? The process of the formation of identity is almost universally traumatic—it is undeniable that Hong Kong’s divergence from the Mainland was precipitated by the British. But we should take identities as we find them to a very great extent; we do not question the English identity because of the harrying of the north or the German identity when it was secured by blood. Identities should be judged by their present effect; the present effect of the Hong Kong identity is to demand freedom. And it is unclear why the central government is the legitimate representative of the Chinese people in the first place; it is not meaningfully elected and goes to great lengths to conceal what can be revealed about the true extent of support for it. But there is another consideration. Even if the bill has a minimal effect, it is still one more step in the salami-slicing strategy of the central government—and the only way to stop such slicing is to resist very firmly every single attempt, even if it seems disproportionate to do so. There will never be tanks or live ammunition in Hong Kong, so to simply wait till there are and then resist would be a thoroughly misguided strategy: one would simply have waited until an arrest on a charge probably concocted in the common law somewhere before being jailed in a still relatively humane jail—but with the consequence that one’s ability to dissent has been curtailed. Further reflexions Tension, and violence, escalated substantially in the aftermath of the visit to the Foreign Office. On 9 June, an estimated million marched, in a city of seven million. If there were ten million on the streets of the United Kingdom no government would last; but the government did not respond. The Wednesday thereafter the second reading of the bill was indefinitely suspended, after violent clashes at the Legislative Council. The police have, in my view rightly, been blamed for escalation then. That same day, it was announced that the second reading of the bill had been indefinitely suspended. On Sunday, two million marched, and an apology was issued. There have been a series of further clashes. Both protesters and police have been inordinately violent to each other, though in many cases it seems that the police created a wide environment of desensitisation to violence. This is true of the environment as a whole: substantial violence first occurred when the police attacked protesters outside the Legislative Council on 12 June. But it is also broadly true of individual incidents; the police did not need to enter New Town Plaza, whence the most galling and distressing footage has emerged. This is not to excuse the behaviour of individual protesters, who in one case seem to have very badly thrashed one policeman. Perhaps appropriate, it was a journalist who protected him, shouting that he was from Hong Kong too. Commentators have become increasingly distressed by this pattern of violence. It is tempting to blame protesters or police, and in individual cases this diagnosis is correct. That, however, would be to ignore the rôle of the Chief Executive in encouraging it. A leadership who truly support Hong Kong’s proud and still extant tradition of peaceful protest would not have withdrawn the bill only after violent clashes, having ignored the voice of a million people, nor would it have required the police to withdraw from a relatively defensible position in the Legislative Council, thus allowing protesters to damage the building. The message of a Chief Executive who relents only when the Legislative Council is besieged is that peaceful marches will be ignored; only violence will attract the attention of the authorities. Moreover, there is good reason to suspect that this is deliberate. First of all, Beijing are paying attention; the South China Morning Post has regularly reported on the despatch of special working groups from Beijing, and pro-Beijing newspapers have reported on the holding of meetings in Shenzhen, with one even including the Chief Executive herself. Second, it is relatively clear what the principal elements of such a plan would be. In allowing and encouraging protesters, Carrie Lam hopes to reduce overall public support for dissidents, with the end of rendering them a small minority who can easily be suppressed when the time is ripe. Violent clashes serve no purpose other than that of the establishment. This reflects an utterly contemptible attitude on the part of the Executive Council to Hong Kong. It is the height of irresponsibility to encourage the destruction of one of the most civilised political cultures in the world for short-term political gain. Pro-establishment types should think very carefully about continued support for this strategy: very few of them genuinely believe that Hong Kong is not ready for universal suffrage or a little redistribution—they support Beijing because they believe in a strategy of limited appeasement to maintain what freedoms they have. If the pan-democrats are successfully sidelined, there will be nobody left to stand up to Beijing other than them; they will no longer receive the patronage of the United Front and the Liaison Office, and will have to face Beijing’s anger—from a position of considerably greater inexperience than that of the pan-democrats. The Chief Executive risks the destruction of Hong Kong qua Hong Kong. Are these people really protesters? Martin Lee suggested not on Radio 4’s Today programme. He may well be right; there is nothing to stop the United Front or HKSAR government from sending provocateurs to implement the strategy outlined above. But there is also nothing to rule out that there are very many genuine protesters amongst the violent. The anger that seethed through students at a recent meeting in Hong Kong University when Mainland students spoke was not the ephemeral product of internal university complaints. A large part of Hong Kong is unspeakably angered by the police, government, and Beijing. Some of them have lost hope due to economic conditions. It is all too plausible that some have been driven to the point of thrashing the police, and that they are not in fact principally provocateurs.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">On finding another letter published</title>
      
      
      <link href="/2019/10/23/another-letter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On finding another letter published" />
      
      <published>2019-10-23T00:00:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2019-10-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>/2019/10/23/another-letter</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/2019/10/23/another-letter/">&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote a letter about an attack by the police with a water cannon on people outside Kowloon Mosque. In searching for it on the SCMP’s website I found another letter of mine.&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Lo (“Protesters see the police as an occupation force”, September 1) suggests that the reason protesters are angered by the actions of the police, even though many Western police forces are more violent, is that they are viewed as an occupation force. There are two problems with this claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the police have in some instances gone beyond international norms: they have beaten commuters on trains, collaborated with or at least turned a blind eye to triad violence against even those who were not involved in the protests, and routinely fired tear gas in dense residential areas. The police claimed that some protesters had changed clothes, as if that would justify thrashing people who were most likely uninvolved passengers. This would not be normal in most European states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, Hongkongers rightly expect higher standards than those in the West. That is because Hong Kong has surpassed the West in many respects. Would Lo wonder why there are complaints about MTR delays that would seem normal in London? Of course he wouldn’t, and that is why it is so ludicrous to think that Hongkongers’ higher expectations need an explanation. Perhaps many Europeans are resigned to the wanton excesses of their police; Hong Kong people aren’t yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lo also wonders why many seem to tolerate violence. I suggest he ask the chief executive. After all, the extradition amendment bill was suspended only after an unlawful assembly on June 12, when a peaceful march by a million people on June 9 had no such impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this serves to address the common argument online that the Hong Kong police are merely copying their Western counterparts and so should not be criticised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot; data-cites=&quot;loo2019c&quot;&gt;Joshua Loo, “Hongkongers Are Right to Expect Better of Their Police,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post: Letters&lt;/em&gt;, September 5, 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scmp.com/comment/letters/article/3025539/hongkongers-rightly-hold-their-police-higher-standards-those-west&quot; role=&quot;doc-biblioref&quot;&gt;https://www.scmp.com/comment/letters/article/3025539/hongkongers-rightly-hold-their-police-higher-standards-those-west&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Joshua Loo</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="letters" />
      

      
        <category term="hong kong" />
      
        <category term="police" />
      
        <category term="scmp" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">I recently wrote a letter about an attack by the police with a water cannon on people outside Kowloon Mosque. In searching for it on the SCMP’s website I found another letter of mine.1 Alex Lo (“Protesters see the police as an occupation force”, September 1) suggests that the reason protesters are angered by the actions of the police, even though many Western police forces are more violent, is that they are viewed as an occupation force. There are two problems with this claim. First, the police have in some instances gone beyond international norms: they have beaten commuters on trains, collaborated with or at least turned a blind eye to triad violence against even those who were not involved in the protests, and routinely fired tear gas in dense residential areas. The police claimed that some protesters had changed clothes, as if that would justify thrashing people who were most likely uninvolved passengers. This would not be normal in most European states. Second, Hongkongers rightly expect higher standards than those in the West. That is because Hong Kong has surpassed the West in many respects. Would Lo wonder why there are complaints about MTR delays that would seem normal in London? Of course he wouldn’t, and that is why it is so ludicrous to think that Hongkongers’ higher expectations need an explanation. Perhaps many Europeans are resigned to the wanton excesses of their police; Hong Kong people aren’t yet. Lo also wonders why many seem to tolerate violence. I suggest he ask the chief executive. After all, the extradition amendment bill was suspended only after an unlawful assembly on June 12, when a peaceful march by a million people on June 9 had no such impact. I hope this serves to address the common argument online that the Hong Kong police are merely copying their Western counterparts and so should not be criticised. Joshua Loo, “Hongkongers Are Right to Expect Better of Their Police,” South China Morning Post: Letters, September 5, 2019, https://www.scmp.com/comment/letters/article/3025539/hongkongers-rightly-hold-their-police-higher-standards-those-west↩︎</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Removing Pandoc’s bibliography</title>
      
      
      <link href="/2019/10/22/removing-bibliography/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Removing Pandoc’s bibliography" />
      
      <published>2019-10-22T00:00:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2019-10-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>/2019/10/22/removing-bibliography</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/2019/10/22/removing-bibliography/">&lt;p&gt;In generating this website I use a combination of Jekyll&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and Pandoc.&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Pandoc converts Markdown files into HTML; I use it because it supports Citation Style Language (CSL),&lt;a href=&quot;#fn3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref3&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which Jekyll’s default Markdown processors do not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am generally of the view that footnotes are the most civilised way to cite others, though my justifications for this mainly apply to books. However, I am a creature of habit, and so like to have full footnotes in lieu of a bibliography when writing on-line too. However, Pandoc seemed to generate both a bibliography and full footnotes, which looked fairly bizarre.&lt;a href=&quot;#fn4&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref4&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that CSL is not as alien as I thought; all that one needs to do to fix this is to remove everything between the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;bibliography&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags on one’s local copy of the CSL file to cause the bibliography to disappear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Vide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pandoc.org/&quot;&gt;Vide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn3&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://citationstyles.org/&quot;&gt;Vide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn4&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/citation-style-language/styles/blob/master/chicago-fullnote-bibliography.csl&quot;&gt;Chicago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref4&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Joshua Loo</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="meta" />
      

      
        <category term="pandoc" />
      
        <category term="csl" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">In generating this website I use a combination of Jekyll1 and Pandoc.2 Pandoc converts Markdown files into HTML; I use it because it supports Citation Style Language (CSL),3 which Jekyll’s default Markdown processors do not. I am generally of the view that footnotes are the most civilised way to cite others, though my justifications for this mainly apply to books. However, I am a creature of habit, and so like to have full footnotes in lieu of a bibliography when writing on-line too. However, Pandoc seemed to generate both a bibliography and full footnotes, which looked fairly bizarre.4 It turns out that CSL is not as alien as I thought; all that one needs to do to fix this is to remove everything between the &amp;lt;bibliography&amp;gt; tags on one’s local copy of the CSL file to cause the bibliography to disappear. Vide.↩︎ Vide.↩︎ Vide.↩︎ I use Chicago.↩︎</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Firing of a water cannon outside Kowloon Mosque: my letter to the SCMP</title>
      
      
      <link href="/2019/10/21/mosque-water-cannon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firing of a water cannon outside Kowloon Mosque: my letter to the SCMP" />
      
      <published>2019-10-21T00:00:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2019-10-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>/2019/10/21/mosque-water-cannon</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/2019/10/21/mosque-water-cannon/">&lt;p&gt;A march led in their personal capacities by members of the Civil Human Rights Front&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; took place on 20th October (Sunday). Jimmy Sham, a prominent member of the Front, was attacked earlier that week by what were alleged to be South Asian assailants, which lead some to demand retribution; members of the pan-democratic camp and Jimmy Sham himself urged others to support ethnic harmony and refrain from blaming ethnic minorities as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some members of the camp as well as ethnic minority Hongkongers assembled outside Chungking Mansions and Kowloon Mosque, two sites important to the South Asian community; at Chungking Mansions, the gathering was uninterrupted and bottled water was handed out. At Kowloon Mosque, however, the police fired a spray so vile that some were sent to hospital at those outside the mosque. Some of the dyed water also hit the mosque, revealing the police’s cavalier attitude to ethnic minorities and other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incident has attracted rather a lot of attention in the international and local media.&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The police have apologised to the mosque and one person outside—Mohan Chugani—who has previously appeared at police rallies.&lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot; data-cites=&quot;lum2019&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref3&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; The &lt;em&gt;SCMP&lt;/em&gt; view this as adequate and wrote an editorial urging calm after the incident.&lt;a href=&quot;#fn4&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref4&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response, I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The editorial of 21 October manages to omit two important points about the firing of a water cannon at Kowloon Mosque. First, the police have apologised only to the mosque, but still accuse those outside of being “dangerous rioters”. This is a blatant falsehood. Video footage shows a few people standing outside peacefully. They included Mohan Chugani, a businessman who has previously spoken at a pro-police rally, and several journalists. It borders on absurdity to call them rioters. Once again the police have chosen to obfuscate instead of acknowledging wrongdoing and apologising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, it is not helpful to smugly claim that “[d]iversity and tolerance have long been seen as characteristic of Hong Kong” when there is so much more to do. The government are complicit in widespread racism: racial discrimination by the police, an educational system that leaves South Asians behind, and discriminatory immigration policy are longstanding grievances that must be addressed. The contrast between a spontaneous move by ordinary citizens to clean the mosque and the tokenistic wheeling out of ethnic minority officers by the police suggests that the people care more about ethnic minorities than the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We shall see whether this letter is published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vide their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/CivilHumanRightsFront/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. An application was made to the police in the name of the Front to hold the march, but the police issued a letter of objection under the Public Order Ordinance: &lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot; data-cites=&quot;1967&quot;&gt;“Public Order Ordinance (Cap. 245)” (1967), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/hk/cap245&quot; role=&quot;doc-biblioref&quot;&gt;https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/hk/cap245&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot; data-cites=&quot;torode2019&quot;&gt;Greg Torode and James Pomfret, “Hong Kong Riot Police Teargas, Chase Protesters, Residents Jeer Officers,” &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;, October 21, 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-hongkong-protests-idUSKBN1X004X&quot; role=&quot;doc-biblioref&quot;&gt;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-hongkong-protests-idUSKBN1X004X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot; data-cites=&quot;2019l&quot;&gt;“Hong Kong Riot Police Fire Tear Gas at Pro-Democracy Demonstrators,” &lt;em&gt;The Irish Times&lt;/em&gt;, October 21, 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/asia-pacific/hong-kong-riot-police-fire-tear-gas-at-pro-democracy-demonstrators-1.4057639&quot; role=&quot;doc-biblioref&quot;&gt;https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/asia-pacific/hong-kong-riot-police-fire-tear-gas-at-pro-democracy-demonstrators-1.4057639&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot; data-cites=&quot;2019m&quot;&gt;“Hong Kong Leaders Apologise to Mosque After Police Sprayed It with Dye,” &lt;em&gt;Mail Online&lt;/em&gt;, October 21, 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-7595205/Hong-Kong-leaders-apologize-mosque-water-cannon-hit.html&quot; role=&quot;doc-biblioref&quot;&gt;https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-7595205/Hong-Kong-leaders-apologize-mosque-water-cannon-hit.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot; data-cites=&quot;cheng2019&quot;&gt;Kris Cheng, “Victims of Water Cannon Outside Kowloon Mosque File Complaints Against Hong Kong Police,” &lt;em&gt;Hong Kong Free Press&lt;/em&gt;, October 22, 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hongkongfp.com/2019/10/22/victims-water-cannon-outside-kowloon-mosque-file-complaints-hong-kong-police/&quot; role=&quot;doc-biblioref&quot;&gt;https://www.hongkongfp.com/2019/10/22/victims-water-cannon-outside-kowloon-mosque-file-complaints-hong-kong-police/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn3&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alvin Lum and Chan Ho-him, “Hong Kong Leader Apologises After Water Cannon Sprays Mosque Entrance,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post&lt;/em&gt;, October 21, 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3033843/hong-kong-protests-city-leader-carrie-lam-and-police-chief&quot; role=&quot;doc-biblioref&quot;&gt;https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3033843/hong-kong-protests-city-leader-carrie-lam-and-police-chief&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn4&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot; data-cites=&quot;editorial2019&quot;&gt;Editorial, “Apology for Firing Water Cannon at Hong Kong Mosque Is a Welcome Move,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post&lt;/em&gt;, October 21, 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3033930/apology-muslim-community-over-firing-water-cannon-mosque-welcome&quot; role=&quot;doc-biblioref&quot;&gt;https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3033930/apology-muslim-community-over-firing-water-cannon-mosque-welcome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref4&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Joshua Loo</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="letters" />
      

      
        <category term="hong kong" />
      
        <category term="mosque" />
      
        <category term="scmp" />
      
        <category term="police" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">A march led in their personal capacities by members of the Civil Human Rights Front1 took place on 20th October (Sunday). Jimmy Sham, a prominent member of the Front, was attacked earlier that week by what were alleged to be South Asian assailants, which lead some to demand retribution; members of the pan-democratic camp and Jimmy Sham himself urged others to support ethnic harmony and refrain from blaming ethnic minorities as a whole. Some members of the camp as well as ethnic minority Hongkongers assembled outside Chungking Mansions and Kowloon Mosque, two sites important to the South Asian community; at Chungking Mansions, the gathering was uninterrupted and bottled water was handed out. At Kowloon Mosque, however, the police fired a spray so vile that some were sent to hospital at those outside the mosque. Some of the dyed water also hit the mosque, revealing the police’s cavalier attitude to ethnic minorities and other people. The incident has attracted rather a lot of attention in the international and local media.2 The police have apologised to the mosque and one person outside—Mohan Chugani—who has previously appeared at police rallies.3 The SCMP view this as adequate and wrote an editorial urging calm after the incident.4 In response, I wrote: The editorial of 21 October manages to omit two important points about the firing of a water cannon at Kowloon Mosque. First, the police have apologised only to the mosque, but still accuse those outside of being “dangerous rioters”. This is a blatant falsehood. Video footage shows a few people standing outside peacefully. They included Mohan Chugani, a businessman who has previously spoken at a pro-police rally, and several journalists. It borders on absurdity to call them rioters. Once again the police have chosen to obfuscate instead of acknowledging wrongdoing and apologising. Second, it is not helpful to smugly claim that “[d]iversity and tolerance have long been seen as characteristic of Hong Kong” when there is so much more to do. The government are complicit in widespread racism: racial discrimination by the police, an educational system that leaves South Asians behind, and discriminatory immigration policy are longstanding grievances that must be addressed. The contrast between a spontaneous move by ordinary citizens to clean the mosque and the tokenistic wheeling out of ethnic minority officers by the police suggests that the people care more about ethnic minorities than the government. We shall see whether this letter is published. Vide their Facebook. An application was made to the police in the name of the Front to hold the march, but the police issued a letter of objection under the Public Order Ordinance: “Public Order Ordinance (Cap. 245)” (1967), https://www.elegislation.gov.hk/hk/cap245↩︎ Greg Torode and James Pomfret, “Hong Kong Riot Police Teargas, Chase Protesters, Residents Jeer Officers,” Reuters, October 21, 2019, https://www.reuters.com/article/us-hongkong-protests-idUSKBN1X004X; “Hong Kong Riot Police Fire Tear Gas at Pro-Democracy Demonstrators,” The Irish Times, October 21, 2019, https://www.irishtimes.com/news/world/asia-pacific/hong-kong-riot-police-fire-tear-gas-at-pro-democracy-demonstrators-1.4057639; “Hong Kong Leaders Apologise to Mosque After Police Sprayed It with Dye,” Mail Online, October 21, 2019, https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-7595205/Hong-Kong-leaders-apologize-mosque-water-cannon-hit.html; Kris Cheng, “Victims of Water Cannon Outside Kowloon Mosque File Complaints Against Hong Kong Police,” Hong Kong Free Press, October 22, 2019, https://www.hongkongfp.com/2019/10/22/victims-water-cannon-outside-kowloon-mosque-file-complaints-hong-kong-police/↩︎ Alvin Lum and Chan Ho-him, “Hong Kong Leader Apologises After Water Cannon Sprays Mosque Entrance,” South China Morning Post, October 21, 2019, https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3033843/hong-kong-protests-city-leader-carrie-lam-and-police-chief.↩︎ Editorial, “Apology for Firing Water Cannon at Hong Kong Mosque Is a Welcome Move,” South China Morning Post, October 21, 2019, https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3033930/apology-muslim-community-over-firing-water-cannon-mosque-welcome↩︎</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">The rule of law: my letter appears in the SCMP</title>
      
      
      <link href="/2019/10/19/scmp-letter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The rule of law: my letter appears in the SCMP" />
      
      <published>2019-10-19T00:00:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2019-10-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>/2019/10/19/scmp-letter</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/2019/10/19/scmp-letter/">&lt;p&gt;Today my letter&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; appeared in the &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post&lt;/em&gt;. The original text I sent follows. I did write this letter rather hastily, because a previous letter I wrote in response to a column&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Lo&lt;a href=&quot;#fn3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref3&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was not published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edwin Choy (14 Oct) writes that perpetrators of “violence, vandalism and other crimes should know from those practising law that their acts constitute serious crimes and are not tolerable in any civilised society.” But the law is never threatened simply because some violate it; it is threatened by the corruption of the institutions that are supposed to uphold it, which Choy skillfully manages to elide in saying merely that “there may be indications that some police officers have used excessive force when dealing with the rioters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 21 July we learnt that the police cannot be trusted to side with the public against triads. On 31 August we learnt that the police consider themselves to be one party of a conflict the other party to which is the public. And from June to October we have learnt that the police have come to see those whom they are meant to serve not as citizens but as “cockroaches.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society can reasonably expect adherence to the rule of law in the way Choy advocates when basic requirements of procedural fairness are met by the police, as they have manifestly not been over the past months. Of course some actions should still be condemned, but not simply in virtue of their illegality; rather, they militate against the principles of justice the achievement of which motivates our creation of the law. The only way that such requirements could be restored is through an independent commission of inquiry—a sensible path that as Choy knows many protesters advocate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I wrote on Facebook,&lt;a href=&quot;#fn4&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref4&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amusingly, my letter is published next to one from one of the most distinguished barristers in Hong Kong in support of Mr Choy. He asks those in agreement with him to “stand up and be counted”: to that I should say that they had their chance in the last elections to the Bar Council, in which over 80% of those eligible voted. Philip Dykes’ stand against threats to the rule of law from both police and protesters was exactly the sort of approach one would have expected from him. Cheng Huan and Mr Choy ought not to assume that they have the backing of a silent majority: a vocal majority seem to have indicated otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot; data-cites=&quot;loo2019&quot;&gt;Joshua Loo, “Hong Kong Police Are Bigger Threat to Rule of Law Than Protesters,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post: Letters&lt;/em&gt;, October 19, 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scmp.com/comment/letters/article/3033219/hong-kong-protesters-may-have-broken-law-police-misconduct&quot; role=&quot;doc-biblioref&quot;&gt;https://www.scmp.com/comment/letters/article/3033219/hong-kong-protesters-may-have-broken-law-police-misconduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot; data-cites=&quot;lo2019&quot;&gt;Alex Lo, “Protesters See the Police as an Occupation Force,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post: Opinion&lt;/em&gt;, September 1, 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3025269/protesters-see-police-occupation-force&quot; role=&quot;doc-biblioref&quot;&gt;https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3025269/protesters-see-police-occupation-force&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn3&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot; data-cites=&quot;lo&quot;&gt;Alex Lo, “Alex Lo,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post&lt;/em&gt;, accessed October 22, 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scmp.com/author/alex-lo&quot; role=&quot;doc-biblioref&quot;&gt;https://www.scmp.com/author/alex-lo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn4&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot; data-cites=&quot;loo2019a&quot;&gt;Joshua Loo, “In Today’s South China Morning Post,” &lt;em&gt;Facebook&lt;/em&gt;, October 19, 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=958830721146139&quot; role=&quot;doc-biblioref&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=958830721146139&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref4&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Joshua Loo</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="letters" />
      

      
        <category term="hong kong" />
      
        <category term="law" />
      
        <category term="scmp" />
      
        <category term="police" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Today my letter1 appeared in the South China Morning Post. The original text I sent follows. I did write this letter rather hastily, because a previous letter I wrote in response to a column2 by Alex Lo3 was not published. Edwin Choy (14 Oct) writes that perpetrators of “violence, vandalism and other crimes should know from those practising law that their acts constitute serious crimes and are not tolerable in any civilised society.” But the law is never threatened simply because some violate it; it is threatened by the corruption of the institutions that are supposed to uphold it, which Choy skillfully manages to elide in saying merely that “there may be indications that some police officers have used excessive force when dealing with the rioters.” On 21 July we learnt that the police cannot be trusted to side with the public against triads. On 31 August we learnt that the police consider themselves to be one party of a conflict the other party to which is the public. And from June to October we have learnt that the police have come to see those whom they are meant to serve not as citizens but as “cockroaches.” Society can reasonably expect adherence to the rule of law in the way Choy advocates when basic requirements of procedural fairness are met by the police, as they have manifestly not been over the past months. Of course some actions should still be condemned, but not simply in virtue of their illegality; rather, they militate against the principles of justice the achievement of which motivates our creation of the law. The only way that such requirements could be restored is through an independent commission of inquiry—a sensible path that as Choy knows many protesters advocate. As I wrote on Facebook,4 Amusingly, my letter is published next to one from one of the most distinguished barristers in Hong Kong in support of Mr Choy. He asks those in agreement with him to “stand up and be counted”: to that I should say that they had their chance in the last elections to the Bar Council, in which over 80% of those eligible voted. Philip Dykes’ stand against threats to the rule of law from both police and protesters was exactly the sort of approach one would have expected from him. Cheng Huan and Mr Choy ought not to assume that they have the backing of a silent majority: a vocal majority seem to have indicated otherwise. Joshua Loo, “Hong Kong Police Are Bigger Threat to Rule of Law Than Protesters,” South China Morning Post: Letters, October 19, 2019, https://www.scmp.com/comment/letters/article/3033219/hong-kong-protesters-may-have-broken-law-police-misconduct↩︎ Alex Lo, “Protesters See the Police as an Occupation Force,” South China Morning Post: Opinion, September 1, 2019, https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3025269/protesters-see-police-occupation-force↩︎ Alex Lo, “Alex Lo,” South China Morning Post, accessed October 22, 2019, https://www.scmp.com/author/alex-lo↩︎ Joshua Loo, “In Today’s South China Morning Post,” Facebook, October 19, 2019, https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=958830721146139↩︎</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">In Abbey</title>
      
      
      <link href="/2019/10/01/abbey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In Abbey" />
      
      <published>2019-10-01T00:00:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2019-10-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>/2019/10/01/abbey</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/2019/10/01/abbey/">&lt;p&gt;There is much else I should like to say, especially about treatment of Mainland people. But I must cut something, and what I am left with is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first line of “March of the Volunteers”, the Chinese national anthem, reads&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Arise, ye who refuse to be slaves!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in recent years at Westminster, democratic political views and values have come to be perceived as somehow opposed to Chinese ethnic identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  How has this happened?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  By one side, China is seen as a despotic régime, descended from that of Chairman Mao. It sees tens of millions of deaths and the myriad of atrocities that collectively overwhelm the human imagination: being forced to kill one’s parents, starvation, and the many tortures invented by millions of human minds bent to the most inhuman of purposes. Today it sees a fundamental unfairness, from concentration camps for Muslims to a lack of recourse when homes are demolished and lungs are poisoned by thoughtless development. Closer to home there are worries that opening a school in China could open us to pressure to curtail the freedom of expression we hold so dear at Westminster. Recent news from Blizzard, the National Basketball Association, and Apple is not encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other side? Here is a thought experiment. Suppose that a hundred of us were sent to a school in India. How would we feel if out of the blue we were asked: “Were your grandparents there at the Amritsar massacre?” “Why do you support the British government when it sells bombs to Saudi Arabia for killing families in Yemen?” “Did you support torture in Britain’s colonial war on the Mau Mau in Kenya?” “Look at the treatment of the Windrush generation. Are all Brits racist?” “What about your betrayal of the people of Diego Garcia?” “Why don’t you realise you are indoctrinated?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In sum, this sort of discourse reduces people to nations, and nations to the worst aspects of their governments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would make two observations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, there is a clear distinction between sensible political discussion about China and Sinophobia. Often, to replace “Chinese government” with “the Chinese” is enough to go from something that could be said in a calm conversation to nonsense about ‘a clash of civilisations’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can all try to find common premises. In moral questions, we can perhaps all agree that ultimately we should strive for fairness, freedom from want, and even human rights. And when discussing how to achieve these aims, we can all recognise the human frailty and selfishness of ruling classes, whether politicians or businessmen, and everyone’s fallibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genuine political discussion isn’t a game, your interlocutor is not the Chinese government, and a cheap rhetorical victory doesn’t free Tibet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, to simply avoid difficult issues is a false economy. A common narrative assigns deference and discipline to China, and open debate to the West. But the history of China is one of peasant revolts just as indicative of a desire for freedom as anything in the history of the West. And it was because of patriotism and the desire for freedom that we resisted the forces of Imperial Japan in 1937. Were we wrong to refuse to bow down?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we should discuss the many difficulties of modern China. To do so without acrimony is entirely possible. It is a very Chinese tradition. And it clearly does not need to involve Sinophobia. We must not make excuses for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Westminster is a bubble. Regrettably, most are shut out. But in its protective embrace, let us try to have some of the discussions that the world needs but too often doesn’t want to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Joshua Loo</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="speeches etc" />
      

      
        <category term="westminster" />
      
        <category term="sinophobia" />
      
        <category term="china" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">There is much else I should like to say, especially about treatment of Mainland people. But I must cut something, and what I am left with is as follows: The first line of “March of the Volunteers”, the Chinese national anthem, reads “Arise, ye who refuse to be slaves!” But in recent years at Westminster, democratic political views and values have come to be perceived as somehow opposed to Chinese ethnic identity.   How has this happened?   By one side, China is seen as a despotic régime, descended from that of Chairman Mao. It sees tens of millions of deaths and the myriad of atrocities that collectively overwhelm the human imagination: being forced to kill one’s parents, starvation, and the many tortures invented by millions of human minds bent to the most inhuman of purposes. Today it sees a fundamental unfairness, from concentration camps for Muslims to a lack of recourse when homes are demolished and lungs are poisoned by thoughtless development. Closer to home there are worries that opening a school in China could open us to pressure to curtail the freedom of expression we hold so dear at Westminster. Recent news from Blizzard, the National Basketball Association, and Apple is not encouraging. The other side? Here is a thought experiment. Suppose that a hundred of us were sent to a school in India. How would we feel if out of the blue we were asked: “Were your grandparents there at the Amritsar massacre?” “Why do you support the British government when it sells bombs to Saudi Arabia for killing families in Yemen?” “Did you support torture in Britain’s colonial war on the Mau Mau in Kenya?” “Look at the treatment of the Windrush generation. Are all Brits racist?” “What about your betrayal of the people of Diego Garcia?” “Why don’t you realise you are indoctrinated?” In sum, this sort of discourse reduces people to nations, and nations to the worst aspects of their governments. I would make two observations. First, there is a clear distinction between sensible political discussion about China and Sinophobia. Often, to replace “Chinese government” with “the Chinese” is enough to go from something that could be said in a calm conversation to nonsense about ‘a clash of civilisations’. We can all try to find common premises. In moral questions, we can perhaps all agree that ultimately we should strive for fairness, freedom from want, and even human rights. And when discussing how to achieve these aims, we can all recognise the human frailty and selfishness of ruling classes, whether politicians or businessmen, and everyone’s fallibility. Genuine political discussion isn’t a game, your interlocutor is not the Chinese government, and a cheap rhetorical victory doesn’t free Tibet. Second, to simply avoid difficult issues is a false economy. A common narrative assigns deference and discipline to China, and open debate to the West. But the history of China is one of peasant revolts just as indicative of a desire for freedom as anything in the history of the West. And it was because of patriotism and the desire for freedom that we resisted the forces of Imperial Japan in 1937. Were we wrong to refuse to bow down? So we should discuss the many difficulties of modern China. To do so without acrimony is entirely possible. It is a very Chinese tradition. And it clearly does not need to involve Sinophobia. We must not make excuses for ourselves. Westminster is a bubble. Regrettably, most are shut out. But in its protective embrace, let us try to have some of the discussions that the world needs but too often doesn’t want to have.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">An open letter: Katie Hopkins</title>
      
      
      <link href="/2019/01/14/letter-hopkins/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An open letter: Katie Hopkins" />
      
      <published>2019-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/2019/01/14/letter-hopkins</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/2019/01/14/letter-hopkins/">&lt;p&gt;We write to strongly protest the decision of Locke to invite Katie Hopkins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is inevitable that discourse will render some uncomfortable, and there is reasonable disagreement as to the priority that should be given to discourse over the safety and feelings of safety of members of the school community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This letter has little to do with such concerns: Hopkins’ statements bear little resemblance to any possible form of reasoned argument, and to the extent that coherent claims emerge, it should be quite obvious both that Hopkins’ statements bear little relation to facts, and that Hopkins’ value judgements largely consist of support for violence and terror for their own sakes. It therefore seems difficult to reconcile Hopkin’s rejection of reason with any reasonable conception of discourse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Civility may demand that we should not rescind an invitation once it has been granted. What is clear is that there should not be a repeat of this sort of situation. The superficial resemblance between the promotion of offence as inherently beneficial and an acceptance that honest debate sometimes will make others uncomfortable masks the costs of this decision. An invitation implies that the speaker in question at least has something cogent to say. If the school must metaëthically err in rejecting the import of feelings, perhaps it will care for the damage to epistemic virtue inherent to any endorsement of one who spurns it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Joshua Loo</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="letters" />
      

      
        <category term="free speech" />
      
        <category term="westminster" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">We write to strongly protest the decision of Locke to invite Katie Hopkins. It is inevitable that discourse will render some uncomfortable, and there is reasonable disagreement as to the priority that should be given to discourse over the safety and feelings of safety of members of the school community. This letter has little to do with such concerns: Hopkins’ statements bear little resemblance to any possible form of reasoned argument, and to the extent that coherent claims emerge, it should be quite obvious both that Hopkins’ statements bear little relation to facts, and that Hopkins’ value judgements largely consist of support for violence and terror for their own sakes. It therefore seems difficult to reconcile Hopkin’s rejection of reason with any reasonable conception of discourse. Civility may demand that we should not rescind an invitation once it has been granted. What is clear is that there should not be a repeat of this sort of situation. The superficial resemblance between the promotion of offence as inherently beneficial and an acceptance that honest debate sometimes will make others uncomfortable masks the costs of this decision. An invitation implies that the speaker in question at least has something cogent to say. If the school must metaëthically err in rejecting the import of feelings, perhaps it will care for the damage to epistemic virtue inherent to any endorsement of one who spurns it.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">On the agreement between the school and Hong Kong Melodious Education Technology Group to open schools in China</title>
      
      
      <link href="/2017/12/06/letter-china/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On the agreement between the school and Hong Kong Melodious Education Technology Group to open schools in China" />
      
      <published>2017-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2017-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/2017/12/06/letter-china</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/2017/12/06/letter-china/">&lt;p&gt;The Chairman of the Board of Governors, the Very Reverend Dr John Hall, wrote to parents notifying them of an agreement to open schools in China.&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ).] I wrote a letter to the headmaster in response.&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://joshualoo.net/westminster/chairman-letter.pdf https://joshualoo.net/westminster/letter-china.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://joshualoo.net/westminster/chairman-letter.pdf&quot;&gt;Vide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://joshualoo.net/westminster/letter-china.pdf&quot;&gt;Vide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-back&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Joshua Loo</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="letters" />
      

      
        <category term="westminster" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">The Chairman of the Board of Governors, the Very Reverend Dr John Hall, wrote to parents notifying them of an agreement to open schools in China.1 ).] I wrote a letter to the headmaster in response.2 https://joshualoo.net/westminster/chairman-letter.pdf https://joshualoo.net/westminster/letter-china.pdf Vide.↩︎ Vide.↩︎</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
</feed>
